you can use a 1x one square to make
sense of the infinite sum 1/2 plus 1/4 +
1/8 and so on first cut the square into
two parts and shade 1/2 then shade 1/2
of the remaining half shading a quarter
then shade 1/2 of the remaining 1/2
shading an eighth continue this process
over and over again each time shading
1/2 of the remaining 1 over 2 to the N
if we continue shading indefinitely that
is if we consider the limiting process
eventually in the limit the entire
Square will be shaded by the sum of
powers of 12 but the square has an area
of 1 so that the infinite sum where K
ranges from 1 to Infinity of 1 2 the K
is equal to 1 another interpretation of
this infinite sum is that 0.1 repeating
in base 2 is equal to 1